Save the date.
Bridesmaids is a comedy, romance film directed by Paul Feig.
Annie's life is a mess.
But when she finds out her lifetime best friend is engaged, she
simply must serve as Lillian's maid of honor.
Though lovelorn and broke, Annie bluffs her way
through the expensive and bizarre rituals.
With one chance to get it perfect, she’ll show Lillian and her
bridesmaids just how far you’ll go for someone you love.
Annie Walker, played by Kristen Wiig.
Lillian Donovan, played by Maya Rudolph.
Helen Harris, played by Rose Byrne.
Officer Rhodes, played by Chris O'Dowd.
Rita, played by Wendi McLendon-Covey.
Becca, played by Ellie Kemper.
Bridesmaids is a 2011 American comedy film directed by Paul Feig
from a screenplay by Annie Mumolo and Kristen Wiig.
It stars Wiig as a woman who experiences a series of misfortunes after being asked to
serve as maid of honor for her best friend, played by Maya Rudolph.
The ensemble cast also features Rose Byrne, Wendi McLendon-Covey,
Ellie Kemper, Melissa McCarthy and Chris O'Dowd.
Actresses Mumolo and Wiig wrote the screenplay after the latter
was cast in Judd Apatow's comedy Knocked Up (2007).
Upon its theatrical release in the United States on May 13, 2011,
Bridesmaids was a critical and commercial success.
It grossed over $306 million worldwide on a $32.5 million budget, and surpassed
Knocked Up to become the top-grossing Apatow Productions film to date.
At the 84th Academy Awards, McCarthy was nominated for Best Supporting
Actress, and Wiig and Mumolo for Best Original Screenplay.
Bridesmaids has served as a touchstone for discussion about women in comedy.
Several publications have ranked it among the best
comedy films of the 21st century.
The film explores themes of jealousy, parent child
relationship, fight, competition, materialism.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.